# 现在是在去往秦镇的路上
We are on the way to Qinzhen now
# 走在这边 你发现路两边有很多人在招呼你
A lot of people at two sides of road say hello to you when you walk on the street
# 他们呢 是招呼你进去吃米皮的
They call you to eat rice noodle
# 这样的场面 原来只在海鲜市场遇到过
It only happened in seafood market before
# 没想到米皮也能竞争成这样的程度
I don’t know rice noodle has competition like this
# 到达目的地
We arrived
# 满大街都是卖米皮的
The whole street are selling rice noodle
# 阿姨 这个刀重不重啊
Aunt, is the knife heavy?
# 13斤
About 13 jin(6.5 kg)
# 您做米皮多久了啊
How long have you do the rice noodle business
# 俺在这干一辈子了
Since i was a kid
# 从十来岁开始一直干到现在
It start since i was about ten years old
# 这是真正的做了三代人了
It’s really been 3 generation
# 切这个米皮都不用看吗
Don’t you even take a look at it when you chop the rice noodle?
# 熟练了 不用看
No need, i’m very good at it
# 阿姨 您切到过手吗
Aunt have you even hurt your finger
# 还没有
Not yet
# 不轻吧 你掂着试试
It’s pretty heavy right? You can try it
# 一般一个女人都拿不起来
A women can’t even lift it
# 这一张米皮是两份 一份是6块钱
One slice rice noodle is two pieces, 6 yuan each pieces
# 阿姨做米皮的年头也很久了 切皮子的速度很快
Aunt working on rice noodle business for very long time, so she chop the rice noodle pretty fast
# 你看做肉夹馍的 需要不停地在案板上剁肉
People who work on Rougamo business, they need to chop meat on the chopping board none stopped.
# 所以呢 他们比较费案板
So they replaced chopping board frequently
# 而像阿姨这种切米皮的 因为一天要切几百张皮子
People like aunt who need chopped hundreds of rice noodle every day
# 他们呢 需要经常换下面的这块布
They need replaced the cloth under the chopping board
# 切好的米皮 蘸上辣子 加上豆芽
Chopped rice noodle with spicy dipping and sprout on it
# 满满的一碗端到跟前
Full of a bowl to serve to you
# 如果觉得这还不够 来瓶冰峰 再加个肉夹馍
If that’s not enough, order a Bingfeng(a soft drink), and a Rougamo
# 体验一下三秦套餐的魅力
Experience the beauty of three qin combo(rice noodle, bingfeng and Rougamo)
# 上头
comfortable
# 关  注
雪 鱼 探 店